<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yaxin Li</title>
    <link>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yaxin Li</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://Cyangem.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Journey to FinTech</title>
      <link>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! I’m thrilled to kick things off by sharing a bit about my journey into the world of data-driven decision-making within FinTech. For as long as I can remember, I’ve been fascinated by numbers and patterns, leading me first into mathematics and finance, and then into the world of data engineering. Now, I have the privilege of applying these skills to the dynamic challenges in credit risk and strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Data Engineering</title>
      <link>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_de_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_de_experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction-from-intern-to-data-engineer&#34;&gt;1. Introduction: From Intern to Data Engineer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My journey as a Data Engineer began with curiosity — how do banks turn millions of data points into insights that drive lending or risk strategy? Over time, I found myself designing ETL pipelines, automating workflows, and even building machine learning pipelines to predict loan delinquency.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before becoming a full-time Data Engineer, I started as a DE intern for 3 months. That experience helped me understand the fundamentals of data pipelines, governance, and business reporting. Later, I joined a bank where I spent 1.5 years as a Data Engineer, supporting business intelligence, automation, and analytics for multiple departments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think Ahead with ACCA</title>
      <link>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_acca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_acca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My ACCA journey began with one idea that resonated deeply with me: “Think Ahead.” I wanted a deep understanding of business and a framework to make strategic, forward-looking decisions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Through completing all foundational modules and three professional-level modules, I gained structured training across areas that directly strengthen my work in financial analytics, business strategy, and data-driven decision-making. Beyond the technical knowledge, the ACCA “Think Ahead” mindset profoundly shaped how I approach challenges — encouraging me to anticipate risks, identify opportunities, and act proactively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Journey into Gen AI &amp; Kaggle</title>
      <link>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_agi_ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://Cyangem.github.io/post/article_agi_ds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Comprehensive Generative AI Framework: Gained a foundational understanding of Generative AI concepts, covering LLM evolution, embeddings, AI agents, domain-specific LLMs, and MLOps practices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Practical Skills: Hands-on experience with the Gemini API, embedding usage, grounding techniques, function calling in LLMs, fine-tuning custom models, and applying MLOps with Vertex AI.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Domain Specialization: Learned to fine-tune models like Gemini for domain-specific tasks, such as analyzing payment behavior, predicting default probabilities, and creating customized credit scoring models using proprietary FinTech data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Real-World Applications: Learned to bridge AI systems with external tools (e.g., SQL, Google Search) and deploy sophisticated AI agents for practical use cases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To empower participants with a deep understanding and practical skills to design, deploy, and manage generative AI solutions, leveraging state-of-the-art tools and techniques to solve real-world challenges efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
